<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-09T16:51:40-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">robertsabec.com</title><subtitle>Robert is a Solutions Engineer at Tealium in San Diego, CA.</subtitle><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hosting site on GitHub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal-site/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hosting site on GitHub" /><published>2020-02-08T20:51:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T20:51:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal-site/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal-site/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github.html">&lt;p&gt;I typically use my personal site for testing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; that require https or to provide a way to demo features or a POC to a client. When deciding to move to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; consider that it is free but limited to only serving flat static html pages.  For me this required changing from my original Angular into page into ‘something else’. I knew I was not interested in the time to manually creating individual HTML pages so enter ‘jekyll’.  Github supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; that helps build your site and provides a built in way to locally preview and test changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/code&gt; only required basic programming skills and beginner Github experience.  I would recommend using GitHub Pages for your personal site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">I typically use my personal site for testing tags that require https or to provide a way to demo features or a POC to a client. When deciding to move to Github pages consider that it is free but limited to only serving flat static html pages. For me this required changing from my original Angular into page into ‘something else’. I knew I was not interested in the time to manually creating individual HTML pages so enter ‘jekyll’. Github supports Jekyll that helps build your site and provides a built in way to locally preview and test changes.</summary></entry></feed>