<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-22T11:23:42-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">robertsabec.com</title><subtitle>Robert is a Senior Solutions Engineer at Tealium in San Diego, CA.</subtitle><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><entry><title type="html">Sous Vide Turkey Thighs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/12/24/sous-vide-turkey-thighs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sous Vide Turkey Thighs" /><published>2020-12-24T08:27:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-12-24T08:27:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/12/24/sous-vide-turkey-thighs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/12/24/sous-vide-turkey-thighs.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;sous-vide-turkey-thighs&quot;&gt;Sous Vide Turkey Thighs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat sous vide - Thighs @ 150F ( Breasts @ 131F )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 to 4 Turkey Thighs ( or breasts )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 TBS olive Oil&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herbs of choice - I prefer sage - few leaves per thigh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarified butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose to sear and brown the turkey thighs before you place in a vacuum sealed bag for the souse vide. This will add a bit more flavor.  You will ultimately sear them at the end to finish for presentation. Dry off your thighs with a paper towel then sear and brown in a hot skillet with olive oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once removed from heat place in bags with sage, salt and sugar.  ( or whatever you want with your turkey ) I will assume you have used a sous vide and are familiar with use and preparing items in a sealed bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sous vide your thighs 12 to 24 hours.  This time span gives you flexibility on when you complete the preration before serving.  They are done at 12 hours but can remain in the sous vide for up to 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove from sous vide and from bag.  Dry and place in the fridge on a plate or cookie sheet for five to tem minutes right before browning.  ( you can skip the fridge step, it only helps in browning without overcooking ). This final step is for presentation.  Your turkey is already perfectly cooked once you remove from the sous vide.  I usually sear in clarified butter but you can choose to grill, broiler or however to want to put a happy glow on your turkey thighs before serving to your guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve with your favorite turkey sides. Since your oven has been free there should be less of a traffic jam in the kitchen!!.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Sous Vide Turkey Thighs</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maple Oat Pecan Scones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/11/14/maple_oat_pecan_scone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maple Oat Pecan Scones" /><published>2020-11-14T08:27:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-14T08:27:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/11/14/maple_oat_pecan_scone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/11/14/maple_oat_pecan_scone.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;maple-oat-pecan-scones&quot;&gt;Maple Oat Pecan Scones&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven - Convection 400 F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When mixing dough, less is more, only mix enough to incorporate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 1/2 cups ( 17.5oz or 1lb 1.5oz ) all purpose flour - APF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup ( 5oz ) whole wheat flour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup oats.  ( this can be Coach’s Oats or Quaker Oats - you can experiments with which one you like better or use the one you have on hand )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 tablespoons sugar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 tablespoons baking powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 teaspoons salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1lb cold unsalted butter - cut into small diced pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2 cup chilled maple syrup ( preferably Vermont )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2 cup chilled water + 2 tablespoons Saco cultured buttmilknpowder ( or 1/2 cup buttermilk )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 large eggs - plus one beaten egg for final egg wash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup lightly roasted and hand crushed pecans ( you can roast raw pecans in 375 oven till fragrant - about 6 minutes, then let cool to room temp before adding to recipe )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a baking sheet with a Sitpat but parchment paper can be used in place of the Sitpat. Mix together most Dry ingredients including cultured buttermilk powder ( not the pecans ) .  Dice up cold to frozen butter and add to mixer on low.  I will typically cover the mixer bowl with a towel to stop spit-out and increase speed of mixer to pulverized and break up the butter chunks.  With mixer on low add wet ingredients (maple syrup, eggs and water all together lightly beaten or mixed before adding into mixer). As the dough is coming together in the mixer add the hand crushed pecans. Adding pecans near the end will help maintain the larger chunks. Empty out the evenly mixed dough out and divide into two balls.  Roll out each into the desired thickness and cut into wedges.  I typically get 8 scones per dough ball or 16 in total.  Place on cookie sheet with Silpat, brush with egg wash and sprinkle additional sugar. Place into a 400-degree oven for about 22 minutes, turn once halfway through.  Remove and cool on rack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve warm with your favorite jam or preserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Maple Oat Pecan Scones</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Short Ribs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/beef/stew/2020/11/08/short_ribs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Short Ribs" /><published>2020-11-08T08:56:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T08:56:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/beef/stew/2020/11/08/short_ribs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/beef/stew/2020/11/08/short_ribs.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;short-ribs-&quot;&gt;Short Ribs .&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 boneless short ribs ( one Costco short rib package ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One medium yellow onion diced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three whole garlic cloves smashed and peeled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eight springs thyme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 to 12 whole peppercorns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 teaspoon salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two bay leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/4 cup APF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One bottle red wine ( Masi Campofiorin or similar blend )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two diced carrot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four diced celery stalks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 tablespoon olive oil ( twice if you remove and replace oil after browing the meat ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two tablesppos butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two tablespoons tomato paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beef stock ( enough to add to cover meat - 6 to 10 oz.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut each of the long short ribs info three sections. Layer these with the onion, thyme, garlic in a food grade container that will hold all the beef and wine. ( Cambro square 4 quart container ) Do not add the carrots and celery to the marinade.  Add peppercorns, salt and entire bottle of wine.  Cover with lid and refrigerate 4 to 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove short ribs from wine and dry meat.  Researve the wine and veggies/herbs. Season each short rib with salt and pepper then dredge in APF.  Add olive oil to oven proof pot or dutch oven. Brown beef in stages to not crowd the pan.  While browing meet seperate wine from onions/garlic/herbs using a strainer,  keeping the ‘wine’ reserved.  Once the last of beef is browned, remove oil from pot and add new olive oil with 2 tablespoons butter.  Add all veggies to pot, including the carrots and celery with the strained items used in the marinade. Saute till onions are translucent, watch heat to not burn garlic cloves.  Add tomato paste, stir in and cook for a few minutes. Pour in reseved red wine and bring to a boil then simmer apporx ten minutes.  Add salt pepper to initially adjust to taste.  Add Beef to pot and then top off with beef stock to just cover meet.  Bring to a simmer, cover and put in 350F oven.  Remove post every 45 minutes to stir and check for tenderness of meat.  Usualy 90 minutes total in oven is sufficient.  If you want to carmelize the beef and stew more then remove or leave lid askew when placing pot back in after the first 45 minutes.  Remove from oven when fork tender and make any final seasoning adjustments now. Serve with a slice of good artisan bread with butter. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good Cabenet accompanies well. Recomendation - any Pride or Sequoia Grove.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Short Ribs .</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Butter Chicken</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/chicken/pressure-cooker/2020/11/07/butter_chicken.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Butter Chicken" /><published>2020-11-07T08:56:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-07T08:56:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/chicken/pressure-cooker/2020/11/07/butter_chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/chicken/pressure-cooker/2020/11/07/butter_chicken.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;butter-chicken-with-carrots-using-a-pressure-cooker&quot;&gt;Butter Chicken with Carrots using a Pressure Cooker.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 to 6 chicken thighs or substitute any 1.5 to 2 lbs chicken cut up into chunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 tablespoons butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One diced onion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One diced carrot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 tablespoons minced fresh ginger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 minced garlic cloves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 tablespoon curry powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 teaspoon salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 teaspoons garam masala&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3/4 teaspoon smoked paprika&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2 can imported San Marzano tomato - about 14 ounces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup heavy cream&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place the butter in pressure cooker on saute, add chopped onions and carrots and season with pinch of salt and pepper.  Saute until onions are translucent. Add ginger and saute 5 more minutes then add garlic and all spices in the Instant Pot . Saute additional 3 to 5 minutes, stirring to make sure not to burn the the garlic and spices. Add tomatoes and chicken, stir to incorporate. Secure lid on pressure cooker and cook on high pressure for 15 minutes. Release pressure then add in cream then reset pressure cooker to simmer and stir occasionally for 15 additional minutes.  Serve as is or with rice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Butter Chicken with Carrots using a Pressure Cooker.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fresh Pasta</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/pasta/2020/08/16/fresh_pasta.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fresh Pasta" /><published>2020-08-16T11:56:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T11:56:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/pasta/2020/08/16/fresh_pasta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/pasta/2020/08/16/fresh_pasta.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;fresh-egg-and-extruded-pasta--&quot;&gt;Fresh Egg and Extruded Pasta -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my notes when experimenting with flour and moister ratios in doughs for extruded and egg pasta.  Extruded pasta will typically be a much drier dough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-fresh-egg-pasta--&quot;&gt;-Fresh Egg Pasta -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 cups ( 10oz ) APF 
2 cups ( 11oz ) Tipo 00 flour
One pinch salt
6 large eggs ( 10.5oz)
2 tablespoons ( 1oz ) olive oil 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TFW = 21oz
TW = 11.5oz + 21oz = 32.5oz
IP = 54%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-extruded-pasta-1--&quot;&gt;-Extruded Pasta 1 -&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;10oz APF or 00 or ratio
4 to 4.5oz H2O
4 large eggs ( 7oz - 1 egg == 1.75oz )
1 3/4 semolina 5.5oz/cup 9.62 oz 
1 3/4 APF 5/oz 8.75oz 
1 tablspoon water
1 teaspoon saly
4 large eggs 7/8 cup liquid volume. 7oz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TFW = 18.37
TW = 25.87
40% H2O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-extruded-pasta-2---bobs-redmill&quot;&gt;-Extruded Pasta 2 - Bob’s Redmill&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 tablespoons olive oil 1oz
2 tablespoons water 1oz
2 eggs 2.5oz
1/2 teaspoon salt
1 1/2 cup semolina 8.25
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;54% H2O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Fresh Egg and Extruded Pasta -</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blueberry-Buttermilk Scones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/08/15/blueberry_muffins.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blueberry-Buttermilk Scones" /><published>2020-08-15T13:56:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T13:56:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/08/15/blueberry_muffins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/recipes/baking/2020/08/15/blueberry_muffins.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;best-blueberry-buttermilk-scones&quot;&gt;Best Blueberry-Buttermilk Scones!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat oven - Convection 375 F&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When mixing dough, less is more, only mix enough to incorporate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use less to no sugar depending on how sweet the blueberries are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 cups ( 15oz ) all purpose flour - APF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup ( 4oz ) cake flour - not self rising&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 tablespoons sugar ( see note above )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 teaspoons baking powder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 ounces cold unsalted butter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup ( 1/2 pint ) blueberries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 cup chilled water + 4 tablespoons Saco cultured buttmilknpowder ( or 1 cup buttermilk )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 large eggs - plus one beaten egg for final egg wash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a baking sheet with a Sitpat but parchment paper can be used in place of the Sitpat. Mix together Dry ingredients including cultured buttermilk powder.  Dice up cold to frozen butter and add to mixer on low.  I will typically cover the mixer bowl with a towel to stop spit-out and increase speed of mixer to pulverized and break up the butter chunks.  With mixer on low add wet ingredients plus blueberries.  Empty out the evenly mixed dough out and divide into two balls.  Roll out each into the desired thickness and cut into wedges.  I typically get 8 scones per dough ball or 16 in total.  Place on cookie sheet with Silpat, brush with egg wash and then into 375-degree oven for 22 minutes, turn once halfway through.  Remove and cool on rack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_0708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blueberry-scones&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">Best Blueberry-Buttermilk Scones!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hosting My Site on GitHub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/website/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hosting My Site on GitHub" /><published>2020-02-08T20:51:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T20:51:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/website/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/website/hosting/2020/02/08/move_personal_site_to_github.html">&lt;p&gt;I typically use my personal site for testing client side &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tags&lt;/code&gt; that require https or to provide a way to demo features or a POC to a client. When deciding to move to &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; I considered that it is free but limited to only serving static html pages.  This required changing my original Angular page into ‘something else’. I knew I was not interested in spending the time to manually create individual HTML pages, so enter ‘jekyll’.  Github supports &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; that helps build your site and provides a built in way to locally preview and test changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/code&gt; only required basic programming skills and beginner Github experience.  I would recommend using GitHub Pages for your personal site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Robert Sabec</name></author><summary type="html">I typically use my personal site for testing client side tags that require https or to provide a way to demo features or a POC to a client. When deciding to move to Github pages I considered that it is free but limited to only serving static html pages. This required changing my original Angular page into ‘something else’. I knew I was not interested in spending the time to manually create individual HTML pages, so enter ‘jekyll’. Github supports Jekyll that helps build your site and provides a built in way to locally preview and test changes.</summary></entry></feed>